Guide to the John Fox Papers, 1784-1892
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
John Fox papers 1784-1892
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Fox, John, 1805-1884.
2,139 Items
Politician and South Carolina legislator, from Lexington (Lexington Co.), S.C.
Family and business papers of John Fox, and of his business associate, William L. Miller. Topics mentioned include the settlement of various estates; the militia; antebellum student life at the University of Virginia and South Carolina College (now the University of South Carolina); railroads; slaves and slavery; cotton production, local politics; secession; living conditions in Richmond during the war; John Fox's post-war debts; a sawmill in Wilcox Co., Ala., owned by brother Daniel and operated by brother Washington Fox; Daniel's service in the Alabama legislature and his comments on Alabama governor Benjamin Fitzpatrick, C. C. Clay, Jr., internal improvements, and public schools; the American Party; crime and law enforcement in the Confederacy; and Reconstruction and African-American politicians during Reconstruction.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The John Fox Papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1949.
Biographical Note
Politician and South Carolina legislator, from Lexington (Lexington Co.), S.C.
Collection Overview
Family and business papers of John Fox, and of his business associate, William L. Miller. Topics mentioned include the settlement of various estates; the militia; antebellum student life at the University of Virginia and South Carolina College (now the University of South Carolina); railroads; slaves and slavery; cotton production, local politics; secession; living conditions in Richmond during the war; John Fox's post-war debts; a sawmill in Wilcox Co., Ala., owned by brother Daniel and operated by brother Washington Fox; Daniel's service in the Alabama legislature and his comments on Alabama governor Benjamin Fitzpatrick, C. C. Clay, Jr., internal improvements, and public schools; the American Party; crime and law enforcement in the Confederacy; and Reconstruction and African-American politicians during Reconstruction.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Clay, C. C. (Clement Claiborne), 1816-1882
Fitzpatrick, Benjamin, 1802-1869
Fox, John, 1805-1884
Fox, Daniel
Fox, Washington
American Party
South Carolina College -- Students
University of South Carolina -- Students
University of Virginia -- Students
African American politicians -- Southern States
Governors -- Alabama
College students -- Southern States
Law enforcement -- Confederate States of America
Cotton manufacture -- South Carolina
Executors and administrators -- South Carolina
Railroads -- Southern States
Reconstruction (U.S. history, 1865-1877) -- South Carolina
Sawmills -- Alabama -- Wilcox County
Secession
Slavery -- South Carolina
Alabama -- Politics and government -- To 1865
Richmond (Va.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
South Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865
South Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1861-1865
Contents of Collection
- John Fox Papers, 1784-1892, (10 boxes, 1 volume, 1 oversize box)
  - Letters and Papers, 1819-1842 (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1843-1849 (Box 2)
  - Letters and Papers, 1850-1856 (Box 3)
  - Letters and Papers, 1857-1871 (Box 4)
  - Letters and Papers, 1872-1880 (Box 5)
  - Letters and Papers, 1881-1892 and undated. (Box 6)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1784-1843 (Box 7)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1844-1857 (Box 8)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1857-1884 and undated. (Box 9)
  - Bound Volumes (Box 10)
  - Volume (Volume L:3377)
  - Letters and Papers, 1833-1880 and undated. (Oversize-box 48)
  - Bills and Receipts, 1831-1855